

INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING STUDENT

Business Intelligence and mechatronics oriented

SKILLS

Soft skills

Teamwork and interpersonal communication

Leadership

Proactivity and active learning

Emotional inteligence

Professional skills

Data science on Python/R

Power BI

LaTex

Solid Edge & LOGO Soft Comfort (Siemens)

Google Workspace

LANGUAGES

English (Upper-Intermediate)

Italian (Advanced)

Spanish (Native)

INTERESTS

Piano musician and teacher

Classical music since 2013. I participated in a piano masterclass in Vittorio Veneto, Italy.

Social projects

Social projects with environmental impact. e.g. Dante Solidario.

Sports

Competitive swimming since 2010. Participated in several national competitions.

CONTACT

bruno-cuevas@hotmail.com

+54 3489 691235

linkedin.com/in/bruno-cuevas-6083051a2

Campana, Argentina, 2804

I am a highly motivated and curious 21 year old student with formal education acquired through an excellent classroom performance. I am looking forward to finishing my double degree in industrial engineering, management oriented, with the goal of improving my decision-making and problem solving skills. In terms of goals, I want to see society benefit from my education and life experiences, hopefully inspiring others along the way.

EDUCATION

Austral University (2019 - 2023)

Degree in Industrial Engineering

Current average: 8,74 (3,3 GPA)

- Favourite fields of study: Data Analytics, Statistics, Operations research.
- Extracurricular courses: International Summit of Adaptative Leadership, Robotics and IT courses
 on Data Science.
- Key experiences:
- Hackathon on analyzing the impact of socio-economic factors in Argentine schools.
- Built a 3d-printed <u>robotic hand</u> controlled by IA, an App and a glove. I also built a <u>beverage</u> <u>dispenser</u> using industrial equipment.
- Invited by professors to visit a chemistry laboratory at Cuyo University in Mendoza (2019).

Dante Alighieri School (2013 - 2018)

High School Diploma oriented in humanities

Final average: 9,13 (3,6 GPA)

- Elected as class captain (2016-2018).
- Extracurricular courses: Ted-Ed talk, Math and Philosophy club. Member of the volleyball team.
- · Key experiences:
 - Started and participated in the Charity Organization called "<u>Dante Solidario</u>" (2018).
 - Reached the final stage on Math national team-olympiad 2016 and on Education First international student award 2017.
 - Invited to participate on Ted-Ed Weekend 2018.
 - Prize for merit in academic performance in Italian and English languages.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

IAE Business School (2021 - Present)

Consultancy project: member of the engineering team

 Research project with the aim of solving problems related to lack of capacity, by developing new commercial proposals and competitive advantages for the important multinational brand: Pernod Ricard.

Austral University (2019 - Present)

Energy Institute

• Responsible for the exploratory analysis of Vaca Muerta data, seeking to develop reports that facilitate access to information and promote progress in the Energy area. I am also working to launch the institute website.

President of the 2019 Class - Industrial Engineering

- Act within the personal environment and transform it for the better. Using leadership and negotiation skills I make decisions that benefit all parties equally,
- Teamwork with other class representatives, partners and administrators to devise plans and goals for upcoming periods.

Assistant Professor on Statistics/Algebra/Chemistry

 I collaborate with students to complete assignments, identifying lagging skills and correct weaknesses by supporting them with helpful study habits and exam strategies.

Escuela Dante Alighieri (2021 - Present)

Calculus Teacher & Innovation Area

- Encouraged class discussions, asking open-ended questions and using real problems to reach student attention.
- Looking forward to innovate in education area by matching technology into learning process.

AWARDS AND HONORS

Austral's Research Congress: 3rd place (2021)

As a spokesperson of statistics cathedra, I introduced an educative data science <u>project</u> to predict results from high school math exams by using machine learning.

"Austral's Academic Excellence Scholarship" and "Galicia's Scholarship"

Galicia Bank and Austral University are investing in my academic career with a full tuition scholarship, allowing me access to high-level education.

Winner of Dante Alighieri School "Honor Award 2018"

Over the course of six years, directives and professors had been evaluating high school students for this award. They have taken into account: proactivity, enthusiasm, perseverance, good disposition and the ability to establish good relationships with peers and superiors.

December 29, 2021

Department of international affairs Politecnico di Milano

Dear Selection Committe,

My name is Bruno Cuevas. I'am an Industrial Engineering student at the Austral University, in Argentina. I stand before you because I have a strong desire of undertaking the Master of Science Degree in Management Engineering at the Polytechnic University of Milan and being considered for the Platinium and Gold Scholarships. By means of this letter, I would like to tell you why I think that I will be able to make the most of this opportunity and what motivates me so much. I wish only to share with you my professional and personal dreams, in order to make an impact on my environment and on society.

Throughout my student life, I have always had great passions. On the one hand, I really enjoyed taking part in the mathematical olympiads held every year in my country; on the other hand, I was also attracted by activities related to establishing relationships or providing me with a realistic view of the world, such as Ted Talks or solidarity projects. These helped me to develop my leadership and communication skills as well as sensitivity to basic human and social issues, which I put into action on a daily basis in my rol as class president at my university. But that was not the only thing, thanks to swimming and piano I also learned what effort and hard work meant to achieve a goal, the need of persistence and perseverance to reach it. I understood that every effort always has its rewards and that sometimes the reward can be unimaginable. In my case, hours sitting in front of the piano led me to a masterclass in Italy and hours studying led me to the opportunity to pursue an outstanding career in engineering. Today I continue to apply these skills in the numerous of projects I am undertaking at the university.

Why am I interested in a double degree with the Polytechnic University of Milan? To complete this training of excellence and become an engineer who not only excels in decision-making in both private and public spheres, but who is also well trained in the latest innovations. At the same time, studying at a university outside my country, accompanied by students with different cultures, beliefs and experiences, will help me enormously to understand the world with a more holistic view. In today's globalized world, in order to have a real impact, it is necessary to understand people and their cultures. This program is an opportunity for me to immerse myself into a new culture and form relations with like-minded people.

As a future engineer, I am convinced that I have a responsibility towards society. Thanks to everything I have learned at Universidad Austral, today I feel capable of creating and understanding things that would have a positive impact in others, and that is what I want to prepare myself for. In a few years' time, I imagine myself undertaking large and innovative projects whose roots will be the knowledge this experience will give me, and whose driving force will be the person I am. My ultimate goal is to inspire and mobilize people, to drive an improvement in society and to make it more humane: leaving a legacy along the way.

I am more than convinced that I am a good fit for this program. Together with my motivation to keep growing and the high level education offered at the Polytechnic University of Milan , I will be an outstanding engineer and make a positive contribution to society, generating great value to the institution and to my education. I still have a lot to offer. Put me to the test. Yours sincerely,

Bruno Miguel Cuevas

Druno